<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Atlantis-Patch on Team Atlanta</title><link>https://team-atlanta.github.io/categories/atlantis-patch/</link><description>Recent content in Atlantis-Patch on Team Atlanta</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://team-atlanta.github.io/categories/atlantis-patch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Every Agent has its Own Story (1) - Martian: Exploring the Unknown with Sophisticated Tools</title><link>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-agent-martian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-agent-martian/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we mentioned in our previous blog post, we enhanced the patching capabilities of Atlantis by ensembling multiple patch agents. In this series of blog posts, we will introduce each of our patch agents in detail and explain the rationale behind their designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diversity-for-good">Diversity for Good&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To maximize the effectiveness of ensembling, it is crucial to have diverse agents. If all agents are similar, the ensemble will not perform significantly better than any individual agent. Therefore, we intentionally designed our patch agents to be diverse in their approaches, methodologies, and also models used. We newly developed six patch agents, each with its own unique architecture and motivation, as summarized in the table below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ensembles of Agents for Robust and Effective Automated Patching</title><link>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-integration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-integration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-ensemble-for-patching">Why Ensemble for Patching?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the AIxCC competition, finding vulnerabilities is only half the battle. Once a vulnerability is discovered, it must be patched to prevent exploitation. This is where the Atlantis-Patching system comes into play. As the AIxCC&amp;rsquo;s ultimate mission is to make software secure, it awards more points for patching vulnerabilities than for finding them. In particular, the competition rewards &lt;strong>6 points&lt;/strong> for patching a vulnerability, compared to just 2 points for discovering it. As a result, to win the competition, it is crucial to have a robust and efficient patching system that can quickly generate effective patches for discovered vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>