<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ensemble on Team Atlanta</title><link>https://team-atlanta.github.io/tags/ensemble/</link><description>Recent content in Ensemble on Team Atlanta</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://team-atlanta.github.io/tags/ensemble/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vincent, One Puzzle for Our Ensemble Toward High-quality Patches</title><link>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-agent-vincent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-agent-vincent/</guid><description>&lt;p>As mentioned in the previous post, our strategy for patching is to prepare multiple agents to ensure both the robustness and correctness of the system.
To this end, we developed various patch agents, each specialized for different LLM models and tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post, we would like to introduce Vincent agent, one of the patch agents running under our ensemble-based patching system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="right-root-cause-wrong-patches">Right Root cause, Wrong Patches&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What surprised us during the competition was that LLMs alone are already quite doing well at generating proper patches.
Given a sanitizer report, LLMs could freely explore the codebase by itself and reason correctly about the given bug—especially when the problematic code appeared near the call stacks in the report.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ensembles of Agents for Robust and Effective Automated Patching</title><link>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-integration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://team-atlanta.github.io/blog/post-crs-patch-integration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-ensemble-for-patching">Why Ensemble for Patching?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the AIxCC competition, finding vulnerabilities is only half the battle. Once a vulnerability is discovered, it must be patched to prevent exploitation. This is where the Atlantis-Patching system comes into play. As the AIxCC&amp;rsquo;s ultimate mission is to make software secure, it awards more points for patching vulnerabilities than for finding them. In particular, the competition rewards &lt;strong>6 points&lt;/strong> for patching a vulnerability, compared to just 2 points for discovering it. As a result, to win the competition, it is crucial to have a robust and efficient patching system that can quickly generate effective patches for discovered vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>